Inventory of the Donald S. Rothchild papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Donald S. Rothchild papers
1930-2006
2003C84
Hoover Institution Archives
151 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (60.8 linear feet)
The Donald Rothchild papers consist of writings, research materials, and printed matter, all of which relate to Rothchild’s lengthy career as a political scientist. A specialist in the study of modern African politics and society, Rothchild had a particular interest in civil conflict and ethnic relations in post-independence African states and his research interests are reflected in the collection.
Rothchild, Donald S.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2003.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Donald Rothchild papers consist of writings, research materials, and printed matter, all of which relate to Rothchild’s lengthy career as a political scientist. A specialist in the study of modern African politics and society, Rothchild had a particular interest in civil conflict and ethnic relations in post-independence African states and his research interests are reflected in the collection. In addition to writing about the consequences of civil wars in Africa, Rothchild wrote about developments in Ghana, Nigeria, and Kenya. The research materials in the papers parallel Rothchild’s writings, but also include other topics. There are extensive materials relating to the Biafran conflict in Nigeria in the late 1960s and the realization of independence for Zimbabwe. There are also materials relating to Rothchild’s interest in comparative history. These include documents pertaining to conflicts in Northern Ireland and the former Yugoslavia, both of which Rothchild thought could be compared with the history of civil wars in Africa. There are also materials relating to American foreign policy in relation to Africa. The printed matter in the collection is largely comprised of government reports on economic and social matters. There are also a number of pamphlets containing analyses of political developments in various African states. The printed matter is listed by country and date in the finding aid.
Biographical/Historical note
Biographical chronology
1928 Born, New York City
1959 Awarded B.A. degree, Kenyon College
1954 Awarded M.A. degree, UC Berkeley
1958 Awarded doctorate, John Hopkins University
1967-1975 Taught political science, UC Davis
1967 Died
Africa--Economic conditions.; Africa--Foreign relations--United States.; Africa--Politics and government.; Africa--Social conditions.; Civil war.; Ethnic conflict.; International relations.; Peace.; United States--Foreign relations--Africa.
- Speeches and writings, 1964-2005
  - "Safeguarding Nigeria's Minorities," Duquesne Review, 1964 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - "From Federalism to Neo-Federalism in East Africa", 1966 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - "Majimbo", 1966 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    Scope and Contents note
    Book chapter. Includes related correspondence.
  - "African Federations and the Diplomacy of Decolonization", 1967 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - "A Typology of African Supranational Integration", 1967 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - "Integrations by Prolonged Negotiation: The Treaty fo East African Co-operation", 1968 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - "From Hegemony to Bargaining in East African Relations", 1974 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - "Ethnicity, Conflict Avoidance, and the Ghana Military", 1978 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - "Comparative Public Demand and Expectation Patterns in Ghana", 1979 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - "Military Regime Performance: An Appraisal of the Ghana Experience, 1972-1978," Comparative Politics, 1980 July (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - With E. Gyimah-Boadi, "Ghana's Economic Decline and Development Strategies" (book chapter), 1984 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - "The Rawlings Revolution in Ghana: Pragmatism with Populist Rhetoric", 1985 May 2 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - With Robert L. Curry, Jr., "Basic Human Needs: The Development of a Development Strategy", 1986 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - With Timothy Sisk, "The Role of Peacekeeping in African Transitions: April 1990 to March 1992", 1994 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - "Structuring State-Society Relations in African States: Toward an Enabling Political Environment", 1994 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - With Stephen John Stedman, "Peace Operations: From Short-Term to Long-Term Commitment," paper, International Studies Association Annual Meetings, San Diego, California, 1996 April 17 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - "Ethnic Fears, Security Dilemmas, and Conflict Management in Africa", 1997 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - "Conflict Management and Elite Habituation in Post-War Democracy: The Case of Mozambique", 1998 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - "Selective Safety Nets: America's Cautious Engagement with African Peackeeping and Its Consequences," paper, Annual Meeting of the African Studies Association, Chicago, Illinois, 1998 October 29-November 1 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Review of Herbst, Jeffrey, States and Power in Africa: Comparative Lessons in Authority and Control
  - "The Effects of State Crisis on African Interstate Relations (and Comparisons with Post-Soviet Eurasia)", 2002 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - With Nikolas Emmanuel, "U.S. Public Opinion and Intervention in Africa's Ethnic Conflicts," paper, Annual Meeting of the International Studies Association, Portland, Oregon, 2003 February 27 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - "Reconstituting the African State after Civil War", 2003 August 7 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - "Reassuring Weaker Parties after Civil Wars: The Benefits and Costs of Executive Power-sharing Systems in Africa," Ethnopolitics, Vol. 4, No. 3, 2005 September (Box-folder 2: 8)
- Research materials, 1968-1979
  Clippings, papers by others, and reports
  - Writings on Uganda by Apolo Nsibambi, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - U.S. Agency for International Development paper on Uganda, 1979 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Printed matter, 1953-
  - Africa--General, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 2: 10-11)
  - Africa--General, 1971 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Kenya, 1953-1966 (Box-folder 3: 2-6)
  - Uganda, 1965-1972
    - 1965 (Box-folder 3: 7-8)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 3: 9-14)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 3: 15-16)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 3: 17-19)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 3: 20)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 3: 21-26)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 3: 27-33)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 3: 34-37)
  - Africa--General, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
  - Uganda, 1960-1972
    - 1960 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - 1963 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 4: 5-6)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 4: 8-9)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 4: 10-11)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 4: 12-15)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 4: 16)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 4: 17)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 4: 18-19)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Kenya, 1965-1972
    - 1965 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Uganda, 1965-1968
    - 1965 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 5: 10-11)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Kenya, 1958-1968
    - 1958 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - 1960 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - 1961 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Uganda, 1963-1969
    - 1963 (Box-folder 6: 6-7)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - 1968-1971 (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 6: 13-14)
  - Africa--General, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 7: 1-3)
  - Kenya, 1967-1968
    - 1967 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 7: 5-8)
  - Uganda, 1967-1986
    - 1967 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Kenya, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Uganda, 1963-1973
    - 1963 (Box-folder 8: 2-4)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 8: 7)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 8: 8)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 8: 9-12)
- Research materials, 1960-2000
  Clippings, reports, and writings by others
  - Mozambique, 1991-1999 (Box-folder 9: 1-13)
  - Powersharing and peacemaking, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Mozambique, 1985-1997 (Box-folder 10: 2-7)
- Printed matter, 1974-1999
  - NIgeria, 1974-1999
    - 1974 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 11: 2-3)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 11: 4-6)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Africa--General, 1973 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Nigeria, 1966-1987
    - 1966 (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 12: 5-7)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 12: 8-12)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 12: 13-14)
    - 1975-1977 (Box-folder 12: 15)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 12: 16)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 12: 17)
  - Africa--General, 1974 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Nigeria, 1966-1976
    - 1966 (Box-folder 13: 2-4)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 13: 5-12)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 13: 13-22)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 13: 23-25)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 13: 26-27)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 13: 28)
- Research materials, 1962-1971
  - Negotiations, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Kenya, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 14: 2-3)
- Printed matter, 1960-1972
  - Developing countries, 1968 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Racial discrimination, 1968 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Nigeria, 1960-1972
    - 1960 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 14: 7-11)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 14: 12-13)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 14: 14)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 14: 14-15)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 14: 16-17)
- Research materials, 1968-2000
  - Nigeria, 1968-1995 (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
  - Ghana, 1978-2000 (Box-folder 15: 3-8)
- Printed matter, 1968-2000
  - Nigeria, 1972 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Ghana, 1968-2000
    - 1968 (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 16: 3-4)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 16: 6-7)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 16: 8)
- Research materials, 1989
  - Ghana, 1989 (Box-folder 17: 1)
- Printed matter, 1964-1989
  - Ghana, 1980-1989
    - 1980 (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 17: 3-4)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - 1987-1989 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - Nigeria, 1964-1971
    - 1964 (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 17: 8)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 17: 9)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 17: 10-12)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 17: 13)
- Research materials, 1979-1991
  - Ghana, 1980-1991 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - South Africa, 1979 (Box-folder 18: 2)
- Printed matter, 1964-1991
  - Nigeria, 1964-1976
    - 1964 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 18: 4-5)
  - Ghana, 1985-1991
    - 1985 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 18: 7-8)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 18: 9)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 18: 10)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 18: 11-13)
- Research materials, 1972
  - Nigeria, 1972 (Box-folder 19: 1)
- Printed matter, 1962-1981
  - Nigeria, 1962-1981
    - 1962 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 19: 3-5)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 19: 6-7)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 19: 8)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 19: 10)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 19: 11-14)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 19: 15)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 19: 16)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 19: 17)
- Research materials, 1951-2006
  Articles, clippings, notes, pamphlets, reports, and writings
  - International economic constraints: debt, 1977-2005 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Chechnya, 1997 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Noel Kaplowitz: conflict management, 1976-1985 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Chinese-African relations, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - Africa's debt problems, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Global conflict and Africa, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Dependency, 1975 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - French policy in Africa, 1951-1980 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Appomattox, 1975 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - Non-aligned conference, 1970 (Box-folder 20: 11)
  - World public opinion, 1969-1977 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Mandates and trusteeships, 1975 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - African alliances and groupings, 1964-1978 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Economic determinants, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Ideology and national interest in an era of structural dependency, 1981 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Africa and power politics, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - African Economic Community treaty, 1991 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Basic human needs, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - Africa and the United Nations, 1966-2005 (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - Non-alignment, 1968-1990 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - Economic Community of West African States, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - United States and African trade, 2000 (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - Paths to African unity, 1970 (Box-folder 22: 3)
  - Organization of African Unity and conflict resolution, 1965-2003 (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - Cartel arrangements, 1981-2005 (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - United States and HIV/AIDS, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Dependency, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 22: 7)
  - Impact of Africa on world politics, 1960 (Box-folder 22: 8)
  - Chinese-African relations, 1969-1991 (Box-folder 22: 9)
  - Liberation struggles, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 22: 10)
  - Resource reallocation: international, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 22: 11)
  - Arms control, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - Brandt report, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - External democracy promotion, 2000-2005 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - Ghana and structural adjustment, 1992-2002 (Box-folder 23: 4)
  - Kissinger/Carter, 1980-2006 (Box-folder 23: 5)
  - United States and terrorism, 2006 (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - Elements of association: Nigeria, 1982-2005 (Box-folder 23: 7)
  - Democracy promotion, 1997-2006 (Box-folder 23: 8)
  - Namibia, 1982-1996 (Box-folder 23: 9)
  - Multinational corporations and African development, 1982-2005 (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - Bush administration and Africa, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - Integration routes and the Economic Community of West African States, 1990-2002 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - Human rights, 1996 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - South Africa, 1983-2006 (Box-folder 24: 5)
- Research materials, 1970-2005
  - France, 1982-2002 (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - Soviet policy in Africa, 1986-1993 (Box-folder 25: 8)
  - Conflict management, 2004 (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Humanitarian intervention--Liberia, 2005 (Box-folder 25: 10)
  - Bill Clinton, 1998 (Box-folder 25: 11)
  - Economic Community of West African States, 1999 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - East African reading materials, 1967 (Box-folder 26: 2)
  - Ghana, 1957-1972 (Box-folder 26: 3-4)
  - Ghana--Ethnicity, 1969-1994 (Box-folder 26: 5-6)
- Printed matter, 1959-1976
  - Ghana, 1959-1976 (Box-folder 26: 7-8)
- Administrative file
  - Teaching evaluations, 1981-2000
    - 1981 (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 27: 2)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 27: 3)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 27: 4)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 27: 5)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 27: 6)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 27: 7)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Syllabi, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 27: 9-10)
  - Teaching evaluatioins, 1985-1997
    - 1985 (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 28: 2-3)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 28: 4)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 28: 5-7)
    - 1992-1993 (Box-folder 28: 8)
    - 1996-1997 (Box-folder 28: 9)
- Research materials, 1959-1986
  - Trade unions, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 28: 10)
  - Western impact on African society, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 28: 11)
  - Imperial penetration of the Congo, 1970 (Box-folder 28: 12)
  - Problem of tribalism, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 28: 13)
  - Colonial status to independence: Nigeria, 1970 (Box-folder 28: 14)
  - Colonial status to indpendence: Congo, 1970 (Box-folder 28: 15)
  - British House of Commons, 1964 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - British House of Lords, 1964 (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - British monarchy, 1959-1986 (Box-folder 29: 3)
  - Britain: party structure, 1960-1980 (Box-folder 29: 4)
  - Britain: environment, 1975 (Box-folder 29: 5)
  - British economy, 1986 (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - British constitution, 1960 (Box-folder 29: 7)
  - British cabinet, 1974-1981 (Box-folder 29: 8)
  - British parties and elections, 1966-1987 (Box-folder 29: 9)
  - Policy analysis, 1980 (Box-folder 29: 10)
  - Modernization, 1980 (Box-folder 29: 11)
  - American interest in the British model, 1980 (Box-folder 29: 12)
  - Systems theory, 1986 (Box-folder 29: 13)
  - Soviet ideology, 1985 (Box-folder 29: 14)
  - Comparing decisional systems, 1985 (Box-folder 29: 15)
  - Introduction: comparative politics, 1985 (Box-folder 29: 16)
  - State-society relations, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 29: 17)
  - Rousseau and the developing societies, 1969 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Africa: general background, 1965 (Box-folder 30: 2)
  - East African federation, 1987-2001 (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - Africa and the European Economic Community, 1970-2000 (Box-folder 30: 4)
  - British interest groups, 1960 (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Britain: constituency control, 1962 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - British civil service, 1960 (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - Party principles: Britain, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 30: 9)
  - Britain: devolution, 1974 (Box-folder 30: 10)
- Administrative file, 1969-2006
  - Examinations, 1969-2006 (Box-folder 30: 11)
  - Teaching evaluations, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 30: 12-14)
  - Examinations, 1963-1989 (Box-folder 31: 1-2)
- Research materials, 1960-2006
  - Secession, 2004 (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - Triggering and escalation, 2005 (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - International managment of ethnic conflict, 1995 (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Systems approach to state-ethnic relations, 1989 (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - Self-determination, 1990-2006 (Box-folder 31: 7-9)
  - "Group Comparison and the Sources of Conflict", 1985 (Box-folder 31: 10)
  - Sammy Smooha, "Control of Minorities in Israel and Northern Ireland", 1980 (Box-folder 31: 11)
  - Implementing peace agreements, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - State as decision-maker, 1990 (Box-folder 32: 2)
  - Terminating ethnic conflicts, 1990 (Box-folder 32: 3)
  - Patterns of conflict: ecpulsion of Ugandan Asians, 1972 (Box-folder 32: 4)
  - Northern Ireland, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - Prevention, 2001 (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - Intervention, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 32: 7-8)
  - Power sharing and peacemaking, 1995 (Box-folder 32: 9)
  - Hegemonial exchange, 1985-2000 (Box-folder 32: 10)
  - Africa's power sharing institutions, 2005 (Box-folder 32: 11)
  - Control model, 1982-2006 (Box-folder 32: 12)
  - Durable peace after civil war, 2003 (Box-folder 33: 1-2)
  - Reconstituting the state after war, 2003 (Box-folder 33: 3)
  - Zimbabwe, 1985 (Box-folder 33: 4)
  - Resource allocation, 1984 (Box-folder 33: 5)
  - Humanitarian intervention, 2001 (Box-folder 33: 6)
  - Conflict-regulating policies, 1969 (Box-folder 33: 7)
  - Conflict on the Horn, 1983 (Box-folder 33: 8)
  - Asian marginal groups in black African states: example of Kenya, 1965 (Box-folder 33: 9)
  - Nation-building, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 33: 10)
  - Kurds, 1970 (Box-folder 33: 11)
  - Conflict-making situations, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 33: 12)
  - Ethnicity, class, and the state, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 13)
  - Managing ethnic conflict in Africa, 1990 (Box-folder 33: 14)
  - Conflict resolution, 1990 (Box-folder 33: 15)
  - Processes of conflict management: Kenya, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 16)
  - Conflict management: Kenya bargaining patterns, 1975 (Box-folder 33: 17)
  - Ethnic conflicts and U.S. foreign policy, 1987 (Box-folder 33: 18)
  - Bargaining, 2000 (Box-folder 33: 19)
  - Ethnic riots, 1965-2003 (Box-folder 33: 20)
  - Regional autonomy, 1997 (Box-folder 33: 21)
  - Federalism, 2000 (Box-folder 33: 22)
  - Regional autonomy, 1997 (Box-folder 33: 23)
  - Partition, 2000-2006 (Box-folder 33: 24)
  - Ethnicity and diffusion, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 33: 25)
  - Ethnic division, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Race and social stratification, 1972 (Box-folder 34: 2)
  - Guyana, 1982 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  - Mediation in Angola, 1989 (Box-folder 34: 4)
  - Ethnicity and conflict avoidance: Ghana, 1978 (Box-folder 34: 5)
  - Analytical approaches to study of comparative interethnic relations, 1975-1991 (Box-folder 34: 6)
  - Selected readings on ethnic conflict, 1982-1994 (Box-folder 34: 7-8)
  - Two-phase implementation process, 2003 (Box-folder 34: 9)
  - Consolidating agreements, 1996 (Box-folder 34: 10)
  - Mediation, 2000 (Box-folder 34: 11)
  - Accomodation through constitutionallism: federalism, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - Accomodation through constitutionalism: regionalism, 1965 (Box-folder 35: 2)
  - Impact of the past, 1970 (Box-folder 35: 3)
  - Army and legitimacy, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 35: 4)
  - Single-party systems: Kenya, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 35: 5)
  - Colonial status to independence: French-speaking West Africa, 1980 (Box-folder 35: 6)
  - MUlti-party Africa, 1965-1978 (Box-folder 35: 7)
  - Federation, 1967 (Box-folder 35: 8)
  - African pluralism and Madison's diversity hypothesis, 1965 (Box-folder 35: 9)
  - Public enterprise, 1975 (Box-folder 35: 10)
  - Single-party systems: Zanzibar, 1970 (Box-folder 35: 11)
  - Single-party systems: French West Africa, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 35: 12)
  - Nationalism and war, 1994 (Box-folder 35: 13)
  - Strong societies and weak states, 1988 (Box-folder 35: 14)
  - Conflict resolution in Africa, 1991 (Box-folder 35: 15)
  - Divided societies, 1979-1994 (Box-folder 35: 16)
  - Organization of African Unity, state sovereignty, and regional security, 1996 (Box-folder 35: 17)
  - Reconfiguring state-ethnic relations in Africa, 1994 (Box-folder 35: 18)
  - Nationalism resurgent, 1995 (Box-folder 35: 19)
  - Political science and African studies, 1983-2005 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - Political institutional transfer, 1990 (Box-folder 36: 2)
  - African state, 1987 (Box-folder 36: 3)
  - Civil society, 2000 (Box-folder 36: 4)
  - Ethnicity and class, 1970-2000 (Box-folder 36: 5)
  - Direct government administration, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 36: 6)
  - Uganda: Ruwenzururu bargaining, 1982 (Box-folder 36: 7)
  - Women, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 36: 8)
  - New African myths, 1967-1980 (Box-folder 36: 9)
  - Political Science 149 course reader, 2005 (Box-folder 36: 10)
  - The quest for the developmental state in Africa, 2005 (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Elections in the Third World, 1995 (Box-folder 37: 2)
  - Military, soft state, and democratization, 2000 (Box-folder 37: 3)
  - Ideology, 1973-2005 (Box-folder 37: 4)
  - Single-party system: Tanzania, 1961-1991 (Box-folder 37: 5)
  - Kenya: administrative-hegemonic regime, 1975-2005 (Box-folder 37: 6)
  - No-party state, 1974-2003 (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - Power sharing, 2005 (Box-folder 37: 8)
  - Bureaucracy, 1972-2005 (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - Education, 1982 (Box-folder 38: 2)
  - Colonial status to independence: Kenya, 1973 (Box-folder 38: 3)
  - Julius Nyere, "Democracy and the Party System", 1970 (Box-folder 38: 4)
  - Uganda rehabilitation, 1968-1988 (Box-folder 38: 5)
  - Ecoonomic scarcity, 1983-1997 (Box-folder 38: 6)
  - Mobilization and distribution of resources, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 38: 7)
  - Political science and African studies, 1976 (Box-folder 38: 8)
  - Women, 1986-1997 (Box-folder 38: 9-10)
  - Press freedom and African nation-building, 1972 (Box-folder 38: 11)
  - United Nations peacekeeping in the Congo, 1966 (Box-folder 39: 1-2)